ZACHARY JOHNSON

125 S Dobson Rd, Apt 2065, Chandler Arizona, 85224 | (480)343-8086 | zachjohnson543@gmail.com

ABOUT ME

Hello, my name is Zachary Johnson. I graduated from Arizona State University with a Bachelors in pure Mathematics in 2021. I am passionate about many areas of Math, but my favorite branches of Math are Number Theory and Cryptology. I am constantly reading Math books to learn more and would like to write my own someday.

During my undergraduate at Arizona State University, I was forced to take my first programming class as a major requirement. I immediately fell in love with coding, and took more programming classes for fun. I am looking for a career that will allow me to marry my passion for both Math and programming.

Aside from academics, my main hobby is Chess. I frequently compete by entering tournaments. The most exciting tournament I entered was the US National Open in Las Vegas. One of my personal goals is to attain the International Master title within 5 years. Another hobby of mine is solving problems from Project Euler. Project Euler is essentially a compilation of Math problems which are intended to be solved computationally.

EDUCATION

School: Arizona State University

Graduation date: May, 2021

Degree: BSc in Mathematics, with a minor in Japanese and certificate in

Cryptology

GPA: 4.0

Relevant classes: Calculus 1,2, and 3, Elementary Statistics, Java Object Oriented

Programming.

Mathematical Structures, Advanced Calculus, Linear Algebra, Real Analysis, Group Theory, Number Theory, Cryptography 1, Cryptography 2, Theory of Combinatorics, and Ring Theory

EXPERIENCE

2019-2020

Subject Area Tutor, ASU

- Tutor students in Mathematics and other relevant subjects
- Collaborated with coworkers to better tutor students
- Created 100+ scripts for videos to better assist students

2017-2019

Assistant Manager, Domino's Pizza

- Made pizza
- Handled customer concerns
- Cleaned store regularly
- Ensured smooth operations
- Responsible for money deposits, as well as checking inventory numbers
- Trained coworkers

2016-2017

Customer Service Representative, Domino's Pizza

- Made pizza
- Handled customer concerns
- Cleaned store regularly

- Certificate of Cryptology
- Strong logic/Critical Thinking
- Python
- Java
- C++
- Linux
- Git
- SQL

AWARDS AND HONORS

- Summa Cum Laude (Arizona State University 2021)
- Moeur Award(Valedictorian) (Arizona State University 2021)
- ASU Dean's list (8) (2017-2021)
- Golden Scholars award in high school (Mesquite High School) (4) (2014-2017)
- Varsity letter in Arizona Chess (2017)
- Captain of high school Chess team (2016-2017)
- President of high school Chess club (2017)

Page 2